let's look at the solution to our till
besides quiz we have a cache that is 32
kilobytes in size and has a 64 byte
block size we have a 4 kilobyte page
size so the question is how many TLB
entries do we need to have a similar hit
rate and miss rate to our cache well if
the processor is just accessing up to 32
kilobytes of memory then our TLB needs
to cover the same amount of memory that
the cache does and that means we need 8
pages now it looks like this would be
the best answer however if the processor
is not accessing all of the data in each
of the pages then we would need more
pages to cover the same amount of memory
because in the cache with a 64 byte
block size we can fit 512 different
blocks and they can be spread around the
whole memory in contrast with 8 entries
in the TLB we can only be accessing 8
different pages while these 500 blocks
theoretically could be in 512 different
pages so our TLB in this case needs to
have up to 512 different pages in order
to have hits for the same data that the
cache does in reality the number of
pages we need for the same hit rate will
be somewhere in between these two so
this is the best answer